Matt Peck

Position Qualifications

Full Stack Developer with over 10 years of international experience, excellent oral and written communication skills, demonstrated interpersonal skills, and proven oversight expertise. Applicant is an integral member of any staff, able to serve organizational needs in leading and directing projects, delegating and completing work in a timely manner. Passionate about JavaScript and modern web technologies, practices, and patterns. High level of integrity in character and work ethic. Strives to perform at the highest level of excellence in every situation.

Technical Skills

- Front End: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ES6+, React, Redux, React Router, D3
- Back End: Node.js, Express, MySQL, AWS (Lambda, API Gateway, S3, Cognito, RDS), Azure, Firebase, Netlify
- Tools: Git, NPM, Webpack, Parcel, Babel, Grunt, Gulp, Postman, Sketch, InVision, Adobe XD

Professional Experience

Full Stack Engineer Masheen (Remote)

1/2019 – Present

Leads a team of engineers building advanced single-page applications utilizing the latest web development and cloud technologies that integrate and depend on custom Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning services. Focused on delivering secure, lean, and performant user experiences by integrating Serverless APIs with highly interactive User Interfaces swiftly with an Agile Scrum approach and these technologies: AWS Lambda, AWS Cognito, Node.js, React, Redux, React-Router.

- Develops clean UIs that contain complex dashboards with data-driven visualizations, intuitive navigation, tasteful animations, and familiar user actions for managing and manipulating application data.
- Integrates application front ends with secure AWS Cognito authenticated logins, role based permissions, and simple user management process with custom emails
- Oversees frontend and backend development teams, providing architectural, development, and integration guidance for ensuring we are: following best design and implementation practices, developing extensible applications, and integrating our applications as efficiently as possible
- Manages project repositories in Github, reviewing pull requests for code quality and development completion as well as enforcing branch flow that aligns with deployment pipelines
- Monitors multiple team workflows using Jira, assigns work to developers, and reviews daily for status updates

Senior Web Developer Booz Allen Hamilton (Remote)

Developed, reviewed, demonstrated, and problem solved with a team of Developers, UX Designers, QA Testers, and Project Leads on a full stack web application leveraging modern web technologies such as: Azure, React, React Router, Redux, Express, and more.

- Fully integrated Redux into React application, abstracting state out of local components into an app-wide store for use across the entire app
- Developed client side routing links for deep linking within the application and between server web pages using React Router
- Developed reusable React components from scratch and using Microsoft's Fabric UI component library
- Developed Node.js / Express RESTful API for managing requests between application and database
- All projects are version controlled with Git and code is reviewed regularly by team members before being deployed to different stages in development
- Used Scrum as the Agile software development approach for iterating through cycles of requirements collection, feature development, testing and deployment

Senior Web Developer Capstone Corporation (Remote)

04/2017 - 12/2017

Senior member of a Front End Development Team that builds custom client-side web applications that solve unique business problems and information shortages for the U.S. Navy.

- Developed financial reporting web app front end using React, Flux (library and pattern), React Router, Bootstrap, ¡Ouery, and SharePoint's REST API
 - An emphasis was placed on browser compatibility to ensure application worked properly on all major browsers, including IE11
 - Utilized SheetJS for parsing excel data on the client
 - Integrated Bootstrap CSS framework in React for quickly bootstrapping User Interface
- Developed dynamic custom Gantt Chart using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, REST API, Bootstrap, and D3
 - o Application requests data from SharePoint List via REST
 - o Builds data visualization on page immediately with D3
- All major JavaScript projects utilize a local build system using Node.js, NPM, Webpack, and Babel
- Team utilizes 1 and 2 week Agile Sprint cycles along with daily Scrum stand ups, Sprint Planning Session, and a Review at the end of each sprint

Web Developer Choisys Technology

06/2016 - 04/2017

Directly consults the Director of Counterintelligence (CI) at Defense Security Service (DSS) as both Web Developer and SharePoint 2010/2013 expert.

- Developed custom master pages for SharePoint 2010/2013 based on client mockups using SharePoint Designer with: C#, ASP.NET, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and jQuery
- Developed an Image Map with Adobe CC that dynamically retrieves company office locations across the U.S. with pop-up dialog boxes and inserts context-based personnel contact information using JavaScript and Bootstrap
- Develops dynamic web tools with Asynchronous JavaScript in JSOM to query and retrieve data from other pages and display cleanly with tabular views using jQuery and Bootstrap
- Design custom page layouts and site templates for organizations using ASP.NET with SharePoint web controls and HTML/CSS
- Tests and debugs web application errors using IE Developer Tools and SharePoint Designer
- Drafts user guides for custom applications and tools developed for customers agency-wide

Front End Developer and Administrator Sonoma Consulting Inc.

12/2015 - 06/2016

Oversaw and managed 7 web domains and 8 domain administrators. Primary responsibilities were developing custom web solutions, promoting user adoption, and implementing IT governance standards.

- Developed custom front end development solutions to fix common template issues utilizing HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Developed custom Help Desk Ticketing web page, improving overall resolution timeline and efficiency
- Provided day to day user support for permissions issues, training, and site creation and development
- Collected business process requirements and built SharePoint Workflows using Nintex Workflow tool to automate tasks, coordinations, and approvals
- Compiled weekly usage reports for tracking organizational participation and usage
- Mapped site collection route topologies for standardizing organizational site layout and relevant site creations
- Developed and maintained governance policy, site standardization, and user training guides

Web Team Lead 02/2010 – 02/2016

United States Air Force

Lead and managed a team that directly supported and maintained Microsoft SharePoint infrastructure with a heavy emphasis on website development and custom HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

- Managed over 200 web application pages, providing custom development compatible with IE9+
- Coordinated the support and maintenance of virtual server (VMware) infrastructure
- Coordinated disaster recovery plan for web application servers
- Created and managed internal websites for organizational offices as required

- Lead and supervised 5 subordinates, together supporting over 22,000 software users
- Team Lead for the SharePoint 2013 Migration Team. Lead the project planning, documenting, and implementation of the migration from SharePoint 2007 to SharePoint 2013
- Responsible for the drafting of IT Governance, User Training Requirements, User How-To Guides, and Training Syllabus
- Served as the Work Center Trainer for 12 Airmen, overseeing the timely and competent training necessary for them to perform air force duties

Education

Bachelor's: BS in Interdisciplinary Studies: Computational Science and Management Information Systems